Syed Zain Jeelani

Islāmābād, Pakistan



sayedzainjeelani@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/zainamroti



03332167003



https://syedzainjeelani.vercel.app/

Summary

A software engineer, love to design and develop apps and like to automate stuff.

I have worked on a ton of technologies, have 4+ years of software development experience, 1.5+ years of Flutter (mobile), and 1+ years of experience with React/Next.js (web development).

I have also worked with different cloud infrastructures, specifically Google Cloud Platform (GCP) with firebase.

Experience



Senior Flutter Developer

Technoshia

Jul 2021 - Dec 2021 (6 months)

Worked on mobile apps for a project similar to Food panda and Ober eats that includes 3 different apps;

- 1. User Food Ordering App with PayPal/Maps
- 2. Restaurant Order management App
- 3. Rider App with google maps integration.

Helped with the overall architecture of the app and integrated User Auth, push notifications, cart system, payment, maps and more.



Full Stack Engineer

Jobit Technologies

Nov 2021 - Present (1 month +)

Managing the Front-end and back-end of Jobit.world App, built with React.js and Node/Express.js, on a part time basis.

Helping to fix many of the UI issues and to implement new features, like payment subscription, video streaming, chat system.



Full Stack Engineer

Freelancer - @suprior5

Mar 2021 - Jul 2021 (5 months)

Built a web app, similar to dextools.io, which utilizes charts and UI to show and analyze crypto pairs.

Created the entire front-end of the app with Next.js/MaterialUI and used lots of third party web3 APIs and built some custom APIs using Node.js as per needs.

Utilized GCP and Firebase services to help with hosting and the back-end. and worked with the mostly used charting library provided by Trading-view

Full Stack Web Developer

Primus Academy Online

Dec 2020 - Feb 2021 (3 months)

A Project, built with React/Next.js to provide a platform for kids to learn words and to form sentences interactively via a drag and drop web tool.

The app includes proper login/signup as a student & Admin panel with authentication and provides lessons for students, their scores and working in a progressive way.

Education



Mehran University of Engineering and Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering 2017 - 2021



The University of Tokyo

Sakura Science Exchange Program, Information Technology 2019 - 2019

Skills

Flutter • React.js • Next.js • Dart • JavaScript • Python (Programming Language) • Software Development • Web Development • Mobile Application Development • Cross-platform Development